<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Project | Coding in the Sky]]></title>
  <link href="http://laputa.io/blog/categories/project/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://laputa.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-19T18:20:12+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://laputa.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[laputa]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Chrome Extension]]></title>
    <link href="http://laputa.io/blog/2013/06/26/my-first-chrome-extension/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T21:02:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://laputa.io/blog/2013/06/26/my-first-chrome-extension</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I just published my first chrome extension <em>Jenkins Monitor</em> in <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/jenkins-monitor/chhebdmlkojbdgadopnedfmoapbeiofi">Chrome Webstore</a>, finally.</p>

<p>I checker my <a href="https://github.com/justlaputa/jenkins-monitor/commits/master">commit history</a> in <a href="https://github.com/justlaputa/jenkins-monitor">Github</a>, it was started at <strong>Apr 24</strong>, and after almost 2 months, I released and published the first version, though it only has very simple and limited features.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The idea is from my daily work, my team use <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/">Jenkins CI</a> every day to build and test our project. Our Jenkins is hosted on <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/">EC2</a>, and the hardware is not so powerful(maybe micro instance, not sure). So sometimes it is very slow to load the Jenkins web page in our browser. Then I decide to find some way to solve this problem. Luckily, Jenkins has <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Remote+access+API">REST API</a>, and I&rsquo;m doing front-end development for some time, making a chrome extension to use the REST API would be a good solution, and I was always thinking to try to develop a chrome extension. So I just started this project, easily.</p>

<p>Still, it surprised me at the first that Chrome Extension development is so easy, all the things I need is just front-end web development technology. HTML, CSS, JS, it is just like make web pages. Thanks to my job, I use them everyday. What&rsquo;s more, I have powerful tools to help me make this extension, like <a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a>, <a href="http://twitter.github.io/bootstrap/">Bootstrap</a>, <a href="http://fortawesome.github.io/Font-Awesome/">Font Awesome</a>, <a href="http://handlebarsjs.com/">Handlebars</a>, <a href="http://gruntjs.com/">Gruntjs</a>, etc.</p>

<p>These tools saved my a lot of time, and makes the implementation simple. I just need to use jQuery <a href="http://api.jquery.com/jQuery.ajax/">ajax</a> call to get all jobs data from jenkins API, then feed the data to handlebar compiled templates, then I have a jenkins jobs list rendered by properly by Bootstrap css:</p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-NKsuyHoB4tc/UcrwpFDiI7I/AAAAAAAAA2g/gcsqCiIXSUw/w1117-h698-no/Screen+Shot+2013-06-24+at+10.36.30+PM.png" title="Jenkins job list" alt="Jenkins Job List" /></p>

<p>Then I want to automatically update the jobs data from jenkins server, I need a timer. I found that I can use chrome extension <a href="http://developer.chrome.com/extensions/alarms.html">alarm</a> API to achieve this.</p>

<p>Last feature before I can release is <em>Notification</em>, I want my jenkins monitor to notify me when there are jobs <code>added/removed/start/done</code>. Not surprisingly, chrome supports <a href="http://developer.chrome.com/extensions/desktop_notifications.html">Desktop Notification</a>, which is just like <a href="http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/notifications/quick/">HTML5 Notification API</a>, it is quite simple to use and I just use one after work night to implement this:</p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-zOOMaQu8ZRo/Ucrwq0p8UfI/AAAAAAAAA2o/MPkDGcFo6lQ/w640-h400-no/Screen+Shot+2013-06-24+at+11.04.31+PM.png%20notification" alt="Jenkins monitor notification" /></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all I need for now! I already asked my colleague to try it and he says it is good. Though it does not have much features,  I still decide to publish it to the chrome webstore. I think making progress is good for me, and I already have plan to improve it in the <a href="https://github.com/justlaputa/jenkins-monitor/issues?milestone=1&amp;page=1&amp;state=open">next version</a>.</p>

<p>If you are interested to try, just install it from <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/jenkins-monitor/chhebdmlkojbdgadopnedfmoapbeiofi">chrome web store</a>, and of cause code contribution is welcomed in <a href="https://github.com/justlaputa/jenkins-monitor/issues?milestone=&amp;page=1&amp;state=open">github</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
